<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[tearin' it up]]></title>
  <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-21T14:14:17-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://lauyeung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Louise Au Yeung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pairing]]></title>
    <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2013/09/21/pairing/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-21T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2013/09/21/pairing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The more I pair program, the more I enjoy it. It&rsquo;s very much like sharing the platform with a buddy. Here are a few pros I&rsquo;ve found:</p>

<p><strong>Pacing</strong>: Sharing the platform makes it easier to time when you should be lifting &ndash; it&rsquo;s much easier to prevent your breaks between sets from being too short or too long. Similarly, pair programming can helps pace yourself&mdash;having someone to code with means that you can talk through your thought process as you work.</p>

<p><strong>Staying Focused</strong>: Having a friend can keep you from getting distracted and keep you on task and in the zone.</p>

<p><strong>Share the Knowledge</strong>: I always learn something new from my partner. Whether it&rsquo;s a lifehack, computer shortcut, or a tip for just doing it better. It&rsquo;s always an educational experience to work with someone.</p>

<p>Pairing can be very uncomfortable at because it requires you try to accommodate someone else&rsquo;s working style and having someone watch you work, but there are some definite benefits. And as with a lot of things, practice helps! Looking forward to more pairing in my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First!]]></title>
    <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2013/08/31/first/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-31T16:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2013/08/31/first</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Humble beginnings! Here&rsquo;s a first post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
