<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: notes | tearin' it up]]></title>
  <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-30T21:59:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://lauyeung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Louise Au Yeung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes from An Event Apart (Boston, April 2014)]]></title>
    <link href="http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2014/04/30/notes-from-an-event-apart-boston-april-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-30T20:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://lauyeung.github.io/blog/2014/04/30/notes-from-an-event-apart-boston-april-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Day 1</h2>


<h3>Understanding Web Design (Jeffrey Zeldman, Founder, Happy Cog and A List Apart)</h3>


<ul>
<li>Anything that gets in the way of users doing what they want to do is bad web design</li>
<li>Web design is more like type-face, architecture &ndash; it steps away and allows the user or content to produce the meaning</li>
<li>Great websites makes interaction easy</li>
<li>Guides you subtly toward your heart’s desire (looks passive, but it’s active)</li>
<li>Can be invisible or in your face</li>
<li>Great web design <em>delights</em></li>
</ul>


<h3>Designing Using Data (Sarah Paramenter, Founder, You Know Who)</h3>


<ul>
<li>Research and data helps back up decisions of why you are changing something (and in turn &ndash; helps to remove resistance to that change)</li>
<li>Avoid vanity metrics (metrics that can’t be acted upon, e.g. hits, pageviews)</li>
<li>Track users and their habits (identify, segment, track)</li>
<li>Leverage Facebook to find out who interacts with your content (use ads and Facebook insights)</li>
<li>Test phrasing (&ldquo;See plans and pricing&rdquo; performed better than &ldquo;Free trial&rdquo; for CTA because it was less commital)</li>
</ul>


<p>Recommended Tools<br>
&ndash; <a href="http://www.truesocialmetrics.com/">TrueSocialMetrics</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="http://www.minimalytics.com/">Minimalytics</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="http://www.crazyegg.com/">Crazy Egg</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="https://www.optimizely.com">Optimizely</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="http://www.browserstack.com/">BrowserStack</a><br></p>

<h3>Responsive Design is Still Hard/Easy! Be Afraid/Don’t Worry! (Dan Mall, Founder & Design Director, SuperFriendly)</h3>


<p><strong>Inventory</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Content inventory: identify all pages on the site and what the page is supposed to do</li>
<li>Pattern inventory: identify the atoms / molecules / organisms on the website (can do this in spreadsheet, photoshop, coded, etc, whatever’s fastest), check out <a href="http://patternlab.io/about.html">Pattern Lab</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Sketch</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Lay everything out simply (use grey boxes)</li>
<li>Number them &amp; block them out on the page</li>
<li>Easy to layout and make responsive</li>
<li>Simple visualization allows for dialog about layout<br>
Check out <a href="http://building.seesparkbox.com/content-prototype/index.php">Sparkbox example</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Assemble</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Create organisms</li>
<li>Presets: list out all the <em>potential</em> organisms for each page</li>
<li>Once organisms and presets are created/prepped (mise en place!), putting pages together should be easy</li>
<li>Check out <a href="http://patternprimer.adactio.com/">Pattern Primer</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Screen Time (Luke Wroblewski, CEO & Co-Founder of Input Factory Inc.)</h3>


<ul>
<li>Know your screen (increasingly mobile)<br></li>
<li>Output (high resolution, widescreen aspect rations, media queries know more than width)<br></li>
<li>Input (support all inputs, communicate what’s possible, screen size is poor proxy but it’s all we’ve got)<br></li>
<li>Posture (design to human scale, environments, not to screen width, distance from device impacts interactions)<br></li>
</ul>


<p>Note: there is a need to optimize tablets for both horizontal and vertical orientations (because both orientations are used!)</p>

<h3>Content/Communication (Kristina Halvorson, Author, Content Strategy for the Web)</h3>


<ul>
<li>Principles: internally motivates us to do things that are good and right, unites us in our day-to-day work<br></li>
<li>Strategy: good strategy will provide constraints and keeps us accountable<br></li>
<li>Process: process should evolve (retrospectives to figure out what works and what doesn&rsquo;t), good process allows us to move together<br></li>
<li>Roles: roles give us a place, use the <a href="http://thebuildnetwork.com/leadership/management/raci-model/">RACI model</a><br></li>
<li>Perceptions: prevent crossed wires or communication issues, ask for clarification when needed, perceptions give way to perspective<br></li>
</ul>


<p>All this stuff is important because:<br>
&ldquo;A study of over 350 people in 6 business units at a financial services company found that the greatest predictor of a team&rsquo;s achievement was how the members felt about one another.&rdquo;<br>
&ndash; Shawn Achor, The Happiness Advantage</p>

<h3>UX Strategy Means Business (Jared Spool, Founder, User Interface Engineering)</h3>


<p>Great content + Great design = Great UX</p>

<p>Business Strategy Priorities<br>
1. Increase revenue<br>
2. Decrease costs<br>
3. Increase new business<br>
4. Increase existing business<br>
5. Shareholder value<br></p>

<p>The 5 strategic priorities are a tool for mapping our design intent into business objectives</p>

<p>Business Model Options<br>
&ndash; Metered paywalls<br>
&ndash; Repurposed content<br>
&ndash; Supporting product sales<br>
&ndash; In-app purchases<br>
&ndash; Alternate channel revenue<br>
&ndash; Content distribution<br>
&ndash; Advertising (ideally avoid this)<br></p>

<p>Advertising: disruptive and corporate (doesn’t add value for the user)<br>
Experience: in the moment of what the user is doing</p>

<h2>Day 2</h2>


<h3>The Long Web (Jeremy Keith, Maker of Websites)</h3>


<p><strong>Progressive Enhancement</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Start using html elements that are not universally supported and because of HTML error-handling, things will still work</li>
<li>Not designing for the lowest common denominator but starting there (e.g. escalators are progressively enhanced stairs)</li>
<li>Make sure you build a strong base</li>
<li>JS doesn’t share the error-handling of HTML/CSS &ndash; what happens when JS doesn&rsquo;t load appropriately?</li>
<li>Need to think long term and having a strong HTML base that is backwards compatible is the way to do it</li>
</ul>


<h3>Responsive Design Performance Budget (Paul Irish, Developer advocate, Google Chrome)</h3>


<p>71% expect sites to load faster on their phone than on their laptop</p>

<p>Bandwidth: amount of information<br>
Latency: lag time
Latency on phones is high which is why it’s slow and the number of users with higher latency is going to increase (more people using mobile)</p>

<p>Aggressive, but good goals:<br>
1. Deliver a fast mobile web page load (show above-fold content in <1 second, serve above-fold content, including critical path CSS, in first 14KB of response)<br>
2. Speed index &lt;1000<br>
3. Delight users<br></p>

<p>Recommended Tools<br>
&ndash; <a href="http://www.webpagetest.org/">WebPageTest</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/">PageSpeed Insights</a>: can run URL through and provides recommendations<br>
&ndash; <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/module">PageSpeed Module</a>: plugin for Apache or NGiNX <br></p>

<h3>The Chroma Zone: Engineering Color on the Web (Lea Verou, W3C CSS Working Group Invited Expert)</h3>


<ul>
  <li>Lightness is not a good deciding metric for whether you should put white or black text on top of color background - relative luminence instead?</li>
  <li>Variables in CSS coming (e.g. currentColor is currently available but limited)</li>
  <li>4-digit hex code (last for alpha)</li>
  <li>HWB = hue whiteness blackness</li>
</ul>




<h3>Mind the Gap: Designing in the Space Between Devices (Josh Clark, Principal, Global Moxie)</h3>


<p>67% users start shopping on one device and continue on another and have to think about each device and also the gaps between</p>

<p>Sometimes don’t even need the internet to have device exchange:<br>
&ndash; WebSockets<br>
&ndash; WebRTC<br>
&ndash; Bluetooth LE<br></p>

<p>Bridge the physical and the digital</p>

<p>Giving digital a physical presence and vice versa</p>

<p>Neat Examples<br>
&ndash; <a href="https://github.com/houseoflegend/happytogether">Making devices happier together =)</a><br>
&ndash; <a href="https://github.com/aral/GrabMagic">Grab screen from tv and put it on the phone</a><br></p>

<h3>Web+: Can the Web Win the War Against Native Without Losing its Soul? (Bruce Lawson, Developer Relations, Opera)</h3>


<p>Reasons people prefer native vs. mobile web
&ndash; Device-specific functionality<br>
&ndash; Offline capability<br>
&ndash; Faster performance (local storage)<br>
&ndash; Familiar<br>
&ndash; Mobile users bookmark by downloading native app (vs. bookmarking in browser)<br></p>

<p>10% of users bookmark a page (computer) and is less on mobile</p>

<p>For mobile users &ndash; installing IS bookmarking</p>

<p>On the web &ndash; the conversation can happen in real time (instant updates vs. downloading updates with a native app)</p>

<h3>How to Champion Ideas Back at Work (Scott Berkun, Author, The Year Without Pants)</h3>


<p>&ldquo;The real designer is the person with the power to make decisions&rdquo;<br><br>
1. Get idea<br>
2. Build it<br>
3. Ship it<br></p>

<p>Between steps 1 &amp; 2 &ndash; need to convince people to build and maybe between 2 &amp; 3 &ndash; need to convince to ship (lots of convincing needs to happen)</p>

<p>Find ways to bring ideas while mitigating risk</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
